RG 074:011, Sidney Miner Genealogical Papers
Connecticut State Library
Sidney Miner genealogical papers
1672-1907
Connecticut State Library
Miner, Sidney, 1805-1881
3 cubic feet
Correspondence, notes, transcripts of oringinal records and family group sheets related to the Miner family.
RG074_011
T003224
Biographical Note
Sidney Miner was born in New London, Connecticut, in 1805, the third son of Frederick Miner, a merchant of New London. Sidney traced his ancestry to Thomas Miner who emigrated from England with Governor John Winthrop and was an early settler in Saybrook. It was his interest in genealogy that led to the formation of this collection.
By trade Sidney was a carpenter, joiner, and store clerk, eventually becoming a partner with Joseph Lawrence in the whaling and sealing business. In 1834 he married Mary A. Ramsdell of Mansfield, Connecticut., with whom he had three children. His wife died in 1843 and the following year he married Lydia Belcher of Granby, Connecticut. Sidney died in 1881. His grandson Sidney H. Miner (1868-1937) was the son of Frederick W. Miner and it was he and Lydia who tried to compile the elder Sidney’s genealogical research into a book for publication.
Scope and Content
Sidney Miner collected family history, and between 1860 and 1880, mailed out circular letters and family group sheets to those with the Miner name throughout the country. This collection consists of samples of his circular letters, blank and completed family sheets, and correspondence providing family histories that Miner planned to compile into a publication. His correspondence is organized in Series 1. One notable letter in the collection is from E.B. Kellogg in 1857 concerning the printing of the Miner coat of arms by Kellogg, a noted Hartford printer.
Sidney died before a book could be completed so his wife Lydia and his grandson Sidney H. continued Sidney's work. Genealogical notes put into an assortment of volumes may have been written by any of the three individuals; as a result, all raw data and drafts of the book have been grouped together in Series 2, Research. Series 3 contains letters to Lydia related to the family history, including from Mary Fosdick about the Lyme, Connecticut, family of Miners and from C.C. Woodward inquiring into the status of the publication. There is also one letter to Sidney H. asking about publication. Among Lydia's papers are several drawings of Minor family coats of arms.
Arrangement
Series 1. Sidney Minor incoming correspondence, 1854-1881
Series 2. Research,1672-1899
Series 3. Lydia and Sidney H. Miner Papers, 1878-1907
Related Material
Minor, Miner family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1936-1991 [CSL call number StLib History Reference Spec.Gen.File Minor]
Index Terms
Persons:
Miner, Lydia Jewett Belcher, 1819-1907; Miner, Sidney, 1805-1881
Miner, Sidney H., 1868-1937
Family Names:
Herndon family; Minor family
Places:
Connecticut -- Genealogy
Document Types:
Coats of arms; Correspondence; Genealogies
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Sidney Miner incoming correspondence, 1854-1881
  - Letters, including a letter from E.B. Kellogg, 1854-1881 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters,(#28-187), 1854-1857 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters,(#204-300), 1857-1860 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters,(#301-398), 1860-1871 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters,(#400-524), 1871-1872 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters (sewn together), 1871-1876 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters, 1857-1877 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters, 1878-1881 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters from black portfolio, 1862-1880 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series 2. Research, 1672-1899
  - Transcriptions and original documents, 1672-1792 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sketch from the life of Richardson Miner, by Richard C. Ambler, read to the Fairfield County Historical Society, 1882 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notebook with death notices, list of individuals wanting the book when published, 1863-1882 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miner cemetery transcriptions (2 volumes), 1882, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - History and genealogical notes (1 volume), after 1872 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Items removed from the preceding volume, 1877-1894 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Nova Scotia records, after 1876 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sketch of Miner coat of arms, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Check book used for genealogical notes, circa 1870 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Items removed from check book, before 1881 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Genealogical notes, after 1872 (similar to item 14) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Data on George Miner, circa 1877 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Genealogical notes, assorted lines and families, 1872-1896 (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
  - "All this book lack the connecting link to pay to record", 1876-1881 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
  - Descendants of Clement Miner, 1873-1880 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Descendants of Ephraim Miner (one item in oversize box), 1876-1879 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - John Miner (2), after 1892 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Descendants of Joseph Miner, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Joshua Miner, after 1893 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Descendants of Judah Miner, 1876-1877, undated (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Descendants of Manassah Miner, 1876-1879, after 1881 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - "An Herauldic Essay" (2 copies), undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Indexes of Miner family names (oversize box), undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Items removed from preceding indexes, 1896-1899 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Miner genealogy by generation (volume), undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miner genealogy book drafts, circa 1899 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
  - Engraved portraits of Sidney Miner, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series 3. Lydia and Sidney H. Miner papers, 1878-1907
  - Incoming letters to Lydia Miner, 1878-1899, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Incoming "Miner family letters" to Lydia Miner, 1883-1889 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Incoming letters from Mary Fosdick to Lydia Miner, 1897-1898 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Incoming letters from C.C. WOodworth to Lydia Miner, 1893-1898 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Notes from Mrs. Chute about Salem, Massachusetts, Miners, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Drawings of Miner family coats of arms and a Wood family grave stone rubbing (oversize folder), undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Non-genealogical letters to Lydia Miner, 1885-1899 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Memorial to Lydia Miner at her death, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Letter to Sidney H. Miner about publishing a book, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Index to unidentified volume and Wheeler & Miner blotter, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)